Marco Catapano

Software Engineer

9+ years of experience in backend application development. I spent these years with the intent of getting continuously better in software engineering. I have always had and I still have curiosity towards languages in order to improve everyday; learning is a never ending process, especially in IT.

About me

- 😭 via Modenese 5, 51100 Pistoia (PT)
- **J** +39 3468772332
- marco.catapano.93@gmail.com
- □ catapano-marco@mail.com
- **#** 12/05/1993
- **𝚱** LinkedIn
- **ℱ** <u>GitHub</u>

Experience

	Software Engineer @ <u>Trade Republic</u>
current - 2022/05	 Maintain, extend, and develop Trading Experience backend systems Go-to person for the instrument search, appropriateness testing, and portfolio chart systems Technical interviews Help in designing new features by writing RFCs and ADRs Tech: Kotlin, Spring, VertX, GH Actions, ScyllaDB, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Snowflake, Kafka, Docker, k8s, LGTM stack, AWS
2022/04 - 2021/05	Software Engineer @ Prima Assicurazioni Develop Agents' platform Backend in Rust Develop Agents' platform Frontend in Elm Tech: Rust, Docker, Elm, GraphQL, k8s, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Datadog
2021/05 - 2018/09	Develop Apache Camel routes Develop Spring REST services DevOps engineering with OCP 3.x and Jenkins Tech: Camel, Spring, Jenkins, OCP, Docker, Java8+, GitLab, RDBMS, ActiveMQ
2018/05 - 2016/09	Backend Developer @ M.E.T.A. Srl Develop features in digital publishing back-ends Extending websites of cultural authorities Tech: PHP, MySQL, Solr, Git, GitLab, Bash
2016/08 - 2015/12	Backend Developer @ Siter SrI Extend company main product either by changing the codebase or by creating external executables (e.g. SOAP consumers, IMAP desktop apps, etc.) Tech: VB6, C#, Java 7, .NET 4, RDBMS
2015/10 - 2015/07	Develop a SOAP service and consumer for the company's main product DB Tech: VB6, C#, Java 7, .NET 4, RDBMS

Misc.

In compliance with the GDPR and Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal details for the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of my rights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned Decree.

Tech skills

Languages

Kotlin, Java, C#, Rust, VB, PHP Basic knowledge: Elm, Python, Golang, sh, F#, C, JS

Frameworks

Spring, VertX, Quarkus, Apache Camel, .NET Core, Actix Web

Tools

Maven, Gradle, NuGet, Cargo, Pip, Git, Docker, IntelliJ IDEA, VSCode, Visual Studio, Insomnia, Postman, Paw

Platforms

OCP, Kubernetes, AWS, EAP, GitHub, GitLab, Quay.io, Datadog, Jira, Terraform, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, ScyllaDB, Terraform, SonarCloud, RabbitMQ, ActiveMQ, JBoss Fuse

Spoken languages

Italian: native English: C1+

Education

Bachelor's Degree in CompSci

@ University of Pisa

Score: 110/110 - with honours

Subjects: algorithms, data structures, FP, OOP, basic math, formal languages, RDBMS, computer arch, networks

Business, Accounting, Programming ("Mercurio" project)

@ I.I.S.S. Antonio Pesenti

Score: 100/100 - no honours
Subjects: economics, applied math, IT